杰森:好吧.你所要做的就是坐在那儿别动.
Jason: Ok.All you have to do is sit here and act nonchalant.
麦琪:杰森,当我们教训迈克的时候,他坐哪呢?
Maggie: Jason, where's Mike going to sit when we ream him?
杰森:就在后面.而且我不是教训.麦琪,我跟他商量.
Jason: Be right back.And I don't ream Maggie, I discuss.
克莉丝:妈妈,妈妈,妈妈.谁要倒霉了?
Chrissy: Mummy, mummy, mummy.Who's in trouble?
麦琪:克莉丝, 什么让你认为有人要倒霉了?
Maggie: Chrissy what makes you think someone's in trouble?
杰森:爸爸告诉我他很高兴,我很清白.
Jason: Daddy told me how happy he was I was a clean slate.
杰森:他的车还没有踪影?
Jason: Still no sign of his car?
克莉丝:迈克要倒霉了.等我告诉本.
Chrissy: Mike's in trouble.Wait till I tell Ben.
麦琪:亲爱的,迈克的车的声音太恐怖了.
Maggie: Honey, Mike's car makes such a horrible sound.
我们不能像正常人一样坐在车里听吗?
Can't we just listen for it inside like normal people?
杰森:唉,上次我们要见他,
Jason: Well, last time we wanted to see him, do you remember what he did?
你还记得他做什么了吗?关掉引擎,空挡滑进车道.
Shut off his engine and slid it into the driveway in neutral.
麦琪:杰森,他知道的.
Maggie: Jason, he knows.
亲爱的,
Honey he knows we are tense and I think he's too smart to try and duck
他知道我们会注意的,我想他不会笨到今天还会耍我们.
us today.
杰森:太聪明了.是的,
Jason: Too smart.Yes,
但是为什么他把这封没有拆开的大学注册单,
then why would he leave this unopened college registration form,
从阳光下看得出今天是截至日期,放在人人都可以找到了地方,
which as direct sunlight reveals was due today,
麦琪?
right out where anybody could find it Maggie?
在梳妆台里的袜子下面,揉成一团.
In the dresser under the socks, tucked away in the back.
麦琪:杰森,我们不必围绕这个转圈了.
Maggie: Jason, we don't have to fool around with any of this.
我们必须给他定下规矩,告诉他该做什么.
We just have to lay down the law and tell him what to do.
杰森:哦,我的清单呢?
Jason: Oh, where is my list?
麦琪:清单?
Maggie: List?
杰森:是的.上面有在退学前必须回答的问题.
Jason: Yes.Questions you must answer before dropping out.
没有清单的话,我不能跟他谈.
I'm not having this discussion without my list.
麦琪:好吧,
Maggie: Fine, go get your list.
去取你的清单.但是在我们逐条谈过之后,
But after we go through it point by point,
你知道我们需要按照我的方式结束这些事情.
you know we are going to end up doing things my way.
杰森:说什么呢?
Jason: What was that honey?
麦琪:我担心你把它给弄丢了.
Maggie: I was so worried you'd lost it.
杰森:不,不,不必担心.我都存到电脑硬盘里了.
Jason: No, no, not to worry.I've got it all on computer disc.
你想要,恩,你想要练练.你扮演迈克,我就扮演自己.
You want to, uh, you want to practice.You be Mike, I'll be me.
麦琪:那么谁来扮演我的角色?
Maggie: Who's going to be me?
杰森:我也来扮演你.
Jason: I'll be you too.
麦琪:那么你扮演我们两个人,而我仅仅扮演迈克?
Maggie: So you get to be both of us and I only get to be Mike?
我要扮演米歇尔 菲佛.
I want to be Michelle Pfeiffer.
杰森:我同意.
Jason: I could live with that.
麦琪:好.
Maggie: Oh.
杰森:来吧,亲爱的.
Jason: Hey come on honey.We need a little practice maybe.
也许我们需要一些练习.角色扮演对我们很重要.那小子很狡猾.
Role play is good for us.Our boy is very tricky.
麦琪:是呀.
Maggie: Yeah.
杰森:你好,迈克.
Jason: Hi Mike.Listen,
听好,你已经仔细考虑过从事表演事业有多么困难?
have you really given thought to how difficult an acting career can be?
去学一门耐以生存的实用的技术,
Don't you think it wise to have a marketable skill you can fall back on?
你不认为很明智吗?你真的想虚度你的青年时代,
Do you really want to drift through your twenties the way you did your teens?
正如少年时代一样?前门.
The front door.
麦琪:怎么了?
Maggie: What about it?
杰森:门没上锁.这样就锁上了.回到车道上.
Jason: Its 8unprotected.That was close.Back to the drive way.
麦琪:杰森,你不该太热衷这件事情.
Maggie: Jason, you shouldn't be enjoying this so much.
杰森:我没有,麦琪.演出开始了!
Jason: I'm not Maggie.Showtime!
麦琪:怎么了?
Maggie: What's the matter?
杰森:这是圈套.
Jason: It's a trick
麦琪:想的周到,
Maggie: Good thinking honey.
亲爱的.迈克可能会料到我们搬出厨房里的凳子在车道上等他,
Mike will probably figure out that we are waiting on kitchen chairs in
然后他从前门进来.
the driveway and try to use the front door.
克莉丝:迈克到底做了什么?
Chrissy: What did Mike do?
本:好的,克莉丝,
Ben: Well Chrissy, its not just one thing.
不止一件事情.妈妈和爸爸知道,迈克一直是……
The way mum and dad see it, Mike's always been....
克莉丝:一直是个令人失望的人.我什么都听到的.
Chrissy: A constant disappointment.I hear things.
本:迈克,出去!妈妈和……哦,仅仅是你.
Ben: Mike, get out!Mum and...Oh it's only you.
开萝尔:只是我!哈.
Carol: Only me! Hu.
克莉丝:妈妈和爸爸正在找迈克;这次的事情有点大.
Chrissy: Mum and dad are looking for Mike; it could be the big one.
开萝尔:好呀,终于可以看到迈克接受审判了,
Carol: Well maybe watching Mike finally brought to justice would perk me up.
真令我振奋.我先去我的房间里看会书 .
I'll be in my room with my library books.
如果是大事就打电话给我,但是要是大事呀.
Call me if it's the big one, but only if it's the big one.
可以我已经说过,我在哥伦比亚大学的第一个星期,
As I may have mentioned, my first week at Columbia University was,
不仅仅累,而且……
not only exhausting, but....
克莉丝,本和开萝尔:比我之前想像的工作多多了.
Chrissy, Ben and Carol: Much more work than I ever expected.
本:你说过.
Ben: You mentioned it.
克莉丝:很多次了.
Chrissy: A lot.
迈克:本杰明,克莉丝廷……
Mike: Benjamin, Christine...
本:迈克,迈克,迈克…….
Ben: Mike, Mike, Mike....
克莉丝:事情搞大了!事情搞大了!
Chrissy: The big one!The big one!
迈克:本杰明,克莉丝廷.听好,
Mike: Benjamin, Christine.Listen calm down.
冷静.如果你们是讨论我父母急着见我这件事的话,
If you're talking about the fact that our parents are a little anxious
我早就知道了.好了,好了.
to see me, I'm well aware of it.Alright.
本:知道就好.迈克,
Ben: Aware of it.
你知道你父亲找到你那个没有拆开的大学注册单了?
Mike, do you know that dad found your unopened college registration form?
迈克:当然.
Mike: Yeah.
本:好.
Ben: Yeah.
克莉丝:你知道他们在前门等着你吗?
Chrissy: Did you know they are waiting for you at the front door?
迈克:他们坐在椅子上累了?
Mike: They got tired of the kitchen chairs hu?
本:我不知道.我怎么刚才没有听见他的汽车声?
Ben: Well I don't get this.How come we didn't hear his car?
克莉丝:我打赌他关掉了引擎,滑进了车道,空挡.
Chrissy: I bet he turned of the engine, slid into the driveway, in neutral.
杰森:他也许可以把车停在街的尽头.
Jason: He may try parking way down at the end of the block.
迈克:在雪佛莱后面的是他的车吗?
Mike: Is that his car behind the Chevy?
杰森:不是,我想…..迈克.
Jason: No, I think that...Mike.
迈克:嗨!你们干的怎么样?
Mike: Hey.How are you guys doing?
麦琪:不是很好.
Maggie: Not well.
迈克:听好,如果你们有时间,我希望和你们商量点事情.
Mike: Hey listen, if you've got some time there are some things id like to discuss.
麦琪:我们没有时间去和你讨论什么事情,
Maggie: We don't have any time to discuss anything cos we have many things
我们还有许多事情要讨论呢.
to discuss.
杰森:亲爱的,让我来处理.
Jason: Honey, I'll handle it.
迈克:听着,我可以先说吗?
Mike: Listen can I go first please?
麦琪:绝对不行.
Maggie: Absolutely not.
迈克:听着,我想和你们谈谈我大学的事情.好吧.大伙们,我想了很多,可能对你们来说这些想法比较愚蠢,但是我已经写了……一份清单.
Mike: Listen, I want to talk to you about my college career.Ok.Now guys
I've been doing a lot of thinking about this and it may sound kind of
silly to you, but I even made...a list
杰森:好,你等会说吧.迈克,由于……一份清单.
Jason: Well, it's just going to have to wait Mike because...a list.
好,好,好.这一点也不愚蠢.继续.
Well, well, well.It doesn't sound silly at all.Proceed.
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Jason,
杰森:放松点,小甜心.我们按程序慢慢来.
Jason: Relax sweetheart.We work with logic.
杰森:你的第二条还是我的第二条?
Jason: Your number two and my number two?
迈克:我的.关于具有一门有用的技术.妈妈.我想进这个学校.
Mike: Mine.About having a marketable skill.And mum.I want to go to school here.
麦琪:菲利普 波顿州教师学校
Maggie: Phillip Boynton State teachers college.
迈克:对.我想,
Mike: Exactly.I mean you guys remember last year when I did that emergency
你们应该还记得去年我临时代课的事情.
substitute teaching.I mean I was so good because not a single one of those
我认为我是个好老师,因为没有一个小孩能骗得了我.
kids could get a single thing passed me.
麦琪:我记得.
Maggie: I remember.
迈克:是呀.现在我知道这意味着可以在大学里多待一些时间,
Mike: Yeah.Now I know it would mean a little more time in college,
但是我的确想去波顿,为获得教师资格证努力.
but I really want to go to Boynton, and work towards a teaching certificate.
杰森:哇.我的孩子去波顿.
Jason: Wow.My boy and Boynton.
迈克:是的,
Mike: Yeah, I mean dad.
爸爸.
It would kind of be like one of those bad guys who starts working for
这好像那些刚学习法律的坏小子.
the law.
麦琪:这已经签了名和办理了一切手续.
Maggie: It's signed in ink and everything.
迈克:这样,就意味着我至少还在车库上住上一年,也许还要从冰箱里偷吃一年的东西.
Mike: Now, it would mean at least another year of me living above the garage and maybe another year of me stealing food out of the refrigerator.
杰森:没关系的.就是不要拿你妈妈的低钠意大利腊肠就是了.
Jason: We don't mind.Just don't touch your mothers low sodium salami.
麦琪:迈克,你是认真的?
Maggie: Mike, you're serious?
迈克:是的,妈妈.我是认真的.
Mike: Yeah mum.I am.
麦琪:但是,你要成为演员的梦想呢?
Maggie: But, what about your dream of being an actor?
迈克:噢,我想,如果我真的优秀的话,可以等我毕业之后.
Mike: Well I figure, if I'm any good, it can wait til after I've graduated.
男人:下一个!83号.
Man: Next!Number 83
迈克:唷.83号.我朋友叫我八十.
Mike: Yo.Number 83.My friends call me eighty.
男人:我相信他们这么叫你.
Man: I'm sure they do.
迈克:米歇尔 西维尔.
Mike: Michael Seaver.
男人:好的,西维尔先生.你可以告诉我们大家一些你最近演戏的经历吗?
Man: Well Mr.Seaver.Would you like to tell us a little bit about your
most recent acting experience
迈克:哦,昨天我就使得我父母相信我已经放弃了表演.
Mike: Uh, well just yesterday I convinced my parents I'd given up acting.
开萝尔:你知道我花了多长时间到家的吗?
Carol: Do you have any idea how long my commute home was?
本:不知道.也不会关心.
Ben: No.Don't care.
开萝尔:我就告诉你们吧.
Carol: Well I'll tell you anyway.
克莉丝:开萝尔,开萝尔,开萝尔.你想和我玩会吗?
Chrissy: Carol, Carol, Carol.You want to play with me?
开萝尔:现在不行,克莉丝.在学校一天我的确太累了.
Carol: Not now Chrissy.I had a really rough day at school.
克莉丝:你该去我们的学前班去.
Chrissy: Well you should have been at my pre-school.
两个看门人撒了三桶木屑,
It took two janitors, three buckets of sawdust, and Mrs.
但是奥博夫人还是滑过了地板.
Orbow still slid across the floor.
开萝尔:我确实累了.过会好吧.
Carol: I'm really tired.Later ok.
克莉丝:迈克说的对.她真无趣.
Chrissy: Mike's right.She is no fun.
开萝尔:一小时四十七分,五十五秒,门到门.
Carol: One hour forty seven minutes, fifty five seconds, door to door.
本:啊?
Ben: Hu?
开萝尔:我所花去的时间.你刚才没在听吗?我今天坐了三次火车.
Carol: My commute.Haven't you been listening?I had to take three trains today.
本:哪辆撞上你的脸了?
Ben: Which one ran into your face?
开萝尔:本,如果由于某种奇迹,
Carol: Ben, if by some miracle you one day get into college on,
哪一天你进入了大学,
say a circus scholarship, head my warning; This is more work,
比如是由于得了杂技奖学金,得听听我的忠告;这是比我一生以来我所做过的更加多,
harder work than I have ever done in my entire life.
更困难的工作.
But do you know what has been the toughest thing about this whole week?
但是你知道这个星期最痛苦的事情吗?就是这个家里没人给句安慰的话.
Nobody in this family seems to give a darn.
本:哦,你还在这啊?
Ben: Oh, are you still here?
开萝尔:不错.老开萝尔什么困难都能克服.
Carol: Good old Carol will bare any cross.
什么负担都能承受.这里的每个人都这么认为.
Any burden and everybody around here acts like it's expected.
但是,当迈克跳进屋子,
When all Mike has to do is jump into the house and say "Great news everyone"
叫道"重大新闻,各位";这样屋子里的所有人就都放下手里的活.
and everyone in this house stops what they are doing.
迈克:各位,重大新闻!
Mike: Great news everybody!
麦琪:迈克,什么呀?
Maggie: What is it Mike.
杰森:嗨.是吗,重大新闻?
Jason: Hey.Alright.Great news?
开萝尔:如果你们都不怪罪我的话,克莉丝有个有趣的恶心故事.
Carol: If you will all excuse me, Chrissy had an interesting vomit story.
麦琪:但是,迈克,你的新闻呢?
Maggie: So, what's you news Mike?
迈克:你们准备好了吗?你们最爱的长子,今天刚刚获得了在百老汇真正演出角色的机会.一份真正的工作.
Mike: Are you ready for this?Your eldest and your favorite, today just got an actual part on an actual off Broadway play.A real job.
杰森:嗨!
Jason: Hey!
迈克:薪水是,达到,每周250美金.
Mike: And the pay is, get this, two hundred and fifty dollars a week.
麦琪:很好.
Maggie: Alright.
本:你将发财了,出名了.
Ben: You'll be rich and famous.
麦琪:太美妙了,这样你就不必放弃你的梦想了.
Maggie: This is wonderful, and you won't have to give up your dreams.
迈克:不放弃.
Mike: No.
杰森:排练跟上课冲突吗?
Jason: Rehearsals won't conflict with class?
迈克:不.一点也不冲突.
Mike: No.No conflict what so ever.
杰森:嗨.什么时候排练?
Jason: Hey.When do you rehearse?
迈克:每周五天.每天八小时.
Mike: Five days a week.Eight hours a day.
麦琪:那么你的州立教师学院的事情怎么办?
Maggie: So what happened to your State Teachers College?
迈克:我没去.
Mike: I'm not going.
麦琪:那么你的申请和其它一切事情是怎么回事?
Maggie: Well what about your application and everything?
迈克:还在手里.
Mike: I still got it.
杰森:等等,等等,等等.这到底是怎么回事,迈克?
Jason: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.Exactly what's going on Mike?
迈克:哦,哦.好,是这样.对于为什么我没有按照我昨天告诉你们的那样去做,我有一个很好的解释.
Mike: Oh, oh.Well, yeah.There's a perfectly good explanation for why I didn't follow through with what I told you guys yesterday.
杰森:什么解释?
Jason: And that is?
迈克:我说谎了.
Mike: I lied.
本:哇!
Ben: Wow!
麦琪:你对我们说谎了?
Maggie: So you lied to us?
迈克:啊哈.
Mike: Uh hu.
杰森:那么你从来就没有想过去波顿?
Jason: So you never had any intention of going to Boynton?
迈克:你已经知道了.我想,如果我昨天照实说了,你们还不暴跳如雷?
Mike: You got it.I mean, wouldn't you guys have been upset if I'd have told you that yesterday?
杰森:因此整件事情都是假的了?
Jason: So this whole story is bogus?
迈克:完全是假的.你们该去看看你们自己脸上的表情.
Mike: Totally.Man, you guys should see the looks on your faces.
杰森:你看着我,但是对我撒谎了.
Jason: So you looked me right in the eyes and you lied?
迈克:不.不止一次,如果你认真会议,我一直都是盯着你的眼睛的呀.
Mike: No.Not once, if you may recall, did I ever look you in the eyes.
杰森:我觉得……我真的被玩弄了.
Jason: I feel...I'm so betrayed.
迈克:被玩弄!爸爸,我获得了角色.
Mike: Betrayed!Dad, I got a part.
杰森:好了!
Jason: Raaaa!
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
麦琪:孩子们,我出去找找你们父亲.
Maggie: Kids, I'm going out to look for your father.
本:找到他应该不是很难.他扛着门呢.
Ben: Shouldn't be too hard to find him.He's carrying a door.
杰森:好的,亲爱的.
Jason: Hi honey.
麦琪:杰森,我真为你担心.
Maggie: Jason, I have been worried sick about you.
杰森:为什么?
Jason: Why?
麦琪:你已经绕着镇子走了三个小时,
Maggie: Well you've been wandering around town for three hours,
而且扛着一扇门.
carrying a door.
杰森:怎么,我应该把它扔在什么地方?
Jason: What, I'm supposed to leave it somewhere?
麦琪:亲爱的,你想干什么?
Maggie: Honey, where are you going?
杰森:向迈克道歉.
Jason: To apologize to Mike.
麦琪:道歉!为什么?他向我们大家说了谎.
Maggie: Apologize!For what?He's the one who lied to us.
杰森:我不该发脾气,麦琪.
Jason: Well I shouldn't have lost my temper Maggie.
如果这曾经是理由的话,这就是了.
If ever there was a time for reason, that was it.
麦琪:杰森,你不该对任何人道歉.
Maggie: Jason, you are not going to apologize to anyone.
该强硬点.该忘记找什么理由.记住,
This is a time to get tough.This is a time to forget reasoning.
我们是父母.我们管他们.我们就告诉他,
Remember, we are the parents.We are in charge.
如果他不回学校,就停止免费供应.
Let's just tell him that if he doesn't go to school, all the freebies stop.
杰森:你说的对.我们休息吧.
Jason: You're right.I'm going to bed.
麦琪:好的.亲爱的,卧室在这边.
Maggie: Good.Honey, the bedroom's this way.
杰森:我们得吃点什么.
Jason: We're going to get a bite to eat.
迈克:好的.
Mike: Yep.
杰森:是爸爸.
Jason: Its dad.
迈克:哦,你需要什么?
Mike: Uh, what do you want?
杰森:门锁了.
Jason: The doors locked.
迈克:啊哈.
Mike: Uh hu.
杰森:来,迈克,打开.
Jason: Well Mike, open up.
迈克:啊,你不再发火了?
Mike: Uh, you're not mad anymore?
杰森:不发火了,事实上我对此感到难受,我得道歉.
Jason: No, in fact I feel real bad about it and I want to apologize.
迈克:好的呀,继续.
Mike: Ok, go ahead.
杰森:我希望面对面对你说,迈克.
Jason: I'd like to do it face to face Mike.
杰森:迈克,打开门,否则我踹门了.瞧,
Jason: Mike, open this door or I'll rip it off.Look,
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: Dad, I've been going through the Boynton catalogue here,
我已经看了波顿的课程目录,如果我们选择周末课程的话,
and you know if I pick up ome weekend courses,
我大概需要12年才能获得教师资格证.
I can probably get my teaching degree in about twelve years.
杰森:迈克,你不必再对我演戏了.
Jason: Mike, you don't have to put on any act with me.Alright.
好吧,我想结束这次谈话,
I wanted to finish the conversation we should have finished earlier before
我们该在我发脾气之前结束.我想得到其中的关键.
I lost my temper.I want to get to the heart of this.The meat.
肉.这很关键.
The very matter.
迈克:你想打我一顿,是不是?
Mike: You're going to hit me aren't you?
杰森:好了.你昨天的清单呢?
Jason: Come on.Where's that list you had yesterday?
我想看看你为什么想留校的一些理由.
I want to go over some of your reasons for why you should stay in school.
迈克:哦,我丢了.
Mike: Uh, uh, I lost it.
杰森:在这.这是我的清单的复印件.迈克,你从你妈妈的内衣抽屉里拿的吧!
Jason: Its right here.This is a Xerox of my list.Mike, you routed through your mothers underwear drawer!
马克:是,你也同样动了我的袜子抽屉.
Mike: Yeah, well you've been in my sock drawer.
杰森:这根本就不是一回事.
Jason: Well it's hardly the same thing.
迈克:跟本去说吧.
Mike: Tell that to Ben.
杰森:我们还是围绕我到这来的原因来谈论吧.
Jason: Can we just stick to the reason I came in here.
迈克:好吧.你来道歉的.
Mike: Right.You were going to apologize.
杰森:迈克,你所做的,你,你,你对我说谎了.
Jason: Mike, what you did, you, you, you lied to me.
迈克:接受道歉.晚安.
Mike: Apology accepted.Goodnight.
杰森: 迈克,你不明白,
Jason: Mike, you don't understand something.
我并不想让你忍受着
I am not trying to make you suffer.
迈克:那么你也已经明白了一些事情.我有我想做的事情.
Mike: Well then you've got to understand something.I've got things that I want to
do
杰森:好.回答我这个问题,迈克.你认为退学和继续你的表演瘾,没有大学学位,你认为值得吗?这实际吗?
Jason: Ok.Answer me this Mike.Do you really think it's a good idea to go off and pursue your acting bug, without a college degree?Is that practical?
迈克:不,不实际.
Mike: No, it isn't.
杰森:好,我们有些共同语言了.
Jason: Ok, we're getting somewhere.
迈克:我想实际,爸爸.
Mike: I don't need to be practical dad.I've got talent.Ok.
我有脑袋.好.
And besides, it is not a bug.
而且,我不是上瘾.
I think that is part of the problem we have here.
我想这就是我们存在的问题的一部分.当我对某些事情感兴趣时,
When I'm interested in doing something it's a bug,
是上瘾;而当开萝尔对什么感兴趣时,那是抱负.
and when Carol's interested you call it an aspiration.
杰森:把你妹妹的抱负排除在外.现在,
Jason: You keep your sisters aspirations out of it.
我正努力能通情达理,迈克.
Now I'm just trying to be reasonable Mike.
迈克:不,你没有;爸爸.
Mike: No, you're not dad.
你只是想说服我做你要我做的事情,因为你要我去做.
You're just trying to talk me into doing what you want me to do,
但是爸爸,我已经二十岁了.
because you want me to do it.But dad, I am twenty years old.Ok.
还有,
I am old enough to vote.
我可以参加选举投票了.为国捐躯,
To die for my country, and if I so desire,
还有如果我愿意,在波多黎各来杯啤酒.
to have a beer in Porto Rico.
杰森:我明白了你多么热衷于演戏的事情.
Jason: Well I can see how serious you are about this acting thing.
迈克:哦,开始是上瘾,现在是事情.继续,爸爸.你为什么不该叫什么就是什么呢.
Mike: Oh, first it a bug, now it's a thing.Come on dad.Why don't you just call it what it is.
杰森:好的,迈克.我知道是什么.
Jason: Ok, Mike I know what it is.It's a sickness Mike.
这是一种病,迈克.我是说,
I mean its one job you got, for two hundred and fifty bucks for what?
干这份工作的二百五十元能持续多久?一周,一个月,一年,
A week, a month, a year, and then what?You'll come running, you'll....
然后呢?你将只能游荡,你将会……你现在太情绪化了.
You are far too emotional here.
迈克:好了,当一个男孩的父亲将他的梦想像一个臭虫一样碾压,想像他怎么去反抗?
Mike: Well how is a guy supposed to react when his dad squishes his dream like a bug?
杰森:哈哈.我们都承认只是臭虫.我想现在讨论这个不是个好主意.我们等到明天早上再讨论吧.
Jason: Ha ha.So we admit it's a bug.You know it's probably a bad idea to discuss this right now.Lets just wait and we'll do it in the morning.
迈克:好的,我们明天早上讨论,爸爸.但是一切不会改变.
Mike: Fine.I'll talk about it in the morning dad.But things are not going to change.
杰森:迈克,你知道你这样对我太强硬了.
Jason: Mike, you know you are making this real tough on me.
迈克:爸爸,这对我来说也不是野餐.明天早上9点我有排练.
Mike: Dad, It's no picnic for me either.I have got a rehearsal tomorrow at nine.
杰森:也许你明天不必去排练,迈克.
Jason: Well maybe you just won't go to that rehearsal Mike.
我意思是说,也许我们之间应该有个妥协.
I mean maybe this, maybe there's a middle ground for us.
我是说,
I mean we've been through a lot of stuff together.
我们已经相互让步很多了,为什么我们不能找出一个折衷方法.
Why can't we just find a compromise?
迈克:那样我也乐意.
Mike: Well I would sure like to.
杰森:好.你觉得什么对你来说是公平的?
Jason: Alright.What sounds fair to you?
迈克:这样,我想,我应该退学,从事表演职业.
Mike: Ok, I think that I should quit school and take the acting job.
杰森:哈哈.这是折衷方法吗?
Jason: Ha ha.How's that a compromise?
迈克:你可以仍然对我吼叫.
Mike: You can still yell at me.
杰森:我告诉你什么是折衷方法.折衷就是你去上学,
Jason: I'll tell you what a compromise is.
周末参加演出.
A compromise is you go to school and you do your plays at the weekend.
迈克:爸爸,演戏可不是这么回事.
Mike: Dad, plays don't work that way.
杰森:可以这样进行几年.
Jason: Well they can for a couple of years.
迈克:爸爸,没有折衷方法.
Mike: Dad, there is going to be no compromise ok.
好.
I am going to do what I want to do,
我做我想做的,你就不得不接受这点吧.
and you are just going to have to live with that.
杰森:好吧,迈克.成交.你需要同样的住房,你需要同样的吃饭,那么你就需要学点什么.你必须是个学生.无论在什么地方学什么.我不管.我听说在加利福尼亚有所游戏主持人的学校.
Jason: Ok Mike.Here's the deal.You want to same rent, you want the same meal plan, then you've got to study something.You've got to be a student.Study anything anywhere.I don't care.I hear in California now they've got a school for game show hosts.
迈克:什么亚历克斯 太贝特技术学院?
Mike: What Alex Trebec Tech?
杰森:我是认真的.
Jason: I'm serious.
迈克:你是说如果我不按照你说的去做,你就让我搬出去?
Mike: So you're saying if I don't do what you say, you're making me move out?
杰森:不是,迈克,你选择搬出去.
Jason: No Mike, you're choosing to move out.
迈克:为什么?
Mike: Why?
杰森:我不知道,你告诉我.我希望你住在这里.
Jason: I don't know, you tell me.I like you living here.
迈克:我也是,爸爸.但是我们在吵什么呢?
Mike: Well me too dad.So what are we fighting about?
杰森:我们不吵了.我要在早上得到你的决定.
Jason: We're not fighting anymore.I want your decision in the morning.
麦琪:起的很早呀.
Maggie: You're up early.
杰森:我需要装几个门.
Jason: I've got doors to hang.
麦琪:几个门?在你说你不会跟迈克谈之后,你跟他谈了吧?
Maggie: Doors plural?Did you talk to Mike after you said you wouldn't?
杰森:昨晚我碰见他了.
Jason: I happened to run into him last night.
麦琪:是不是你在厨房里把餐具弄的咔嗒咔嗒响的时候?
Maggie: Was this about the time you were rattling dishes in the kitchen?
杰森:之后.
Jason: Later.
麦琪:还有?
Maggie: And?
杰森:还有什么?
Jason: And what?
麦琪:他是房东,你是雇工?
Maggie: And he owns the house and you're his handyman?
开萝尔:我走这么早的原因是我想在两个小时之内到达曼哈顿.
Carol: The reason I'm leaving so early is so hopefully I can make it into
如果有人注意到的话.
Manhattan in under two hours.If anybody cares.
麦琪:一天愉快,甜心.
Maggie: Have a good day sweetheart.
杰森:一样.
Jason: Ditto.
开萝尔:妈妈,我可以借用你的香水吗?我的昨天用完了.
Carol: Mum, may I borrow your mace?I used all mine up yesterday.
麦琪:好的,亲爱的.杰森,怎么样?
Maggie: Sure honey.Jason, what happened?
杰森:我们刚才谈了会儿,我想我说服他了.
Jason: Well we just had a little talk and I think I got through to him.
麦琪:你说服他了?真的?
Maggie: You do?Really?
杰森:哦.是真的.
Jason: Uh hu.Really.
麦琪:也许你跟他谈话是正确的.
Maggie: Well maybe it is a good thing you talked to him.
如果我上楼去,我也许会发脾气,
If I'd gone up there I probably would have lost my temper and given him
给他愚蠢的最后通牒.
some stupid ultimatum.
杰森:我去取报纸.嗨,迈克.我可以给你装门吗?迈克?
广播:每个人都在讲我.我不去听他们讲的任何一个单词.只有我大脑里的回声.人们驻足凝视.我见不到他们的脸.只有他们眼睛的影子.我去太阳永远照耀的地方.经过倾盆大雨.
00:20:15,100
Jason: I'm going to go get the newspaper.Hey Mike.Can I hang that door for you?Mike? Radio: Everybody's talking at me.I don't hear a word they're saying.Only the echoes of my mind.People stop and stare.I can't see their faces.Only the shadows of their eyes.I'm going where the sun keeps shining.Through the pouring rain.